<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xml:lang="en">
  <generator uri="http://jekyllrb.com" version="3.4.3">Jekyll</generator>
  
  
  <link href="http://yatindrarao.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" />
  <link href="http://yatindrarao.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" hreflang="en" />
  <updated>2017-07-21T16:34:59+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://yatindrarao.me//</id>

  
    <title type="html">Yatindra Rao</title>
  

  
    <subtitle>Software Engineer sharing knowledge with the world</subtitle>
  

  
    <author>
        <name>Yatindra Rao</name>
      
      
    </author>
  

  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">How To Add Custom Domain And SSL in Heroku</title>
      
      <link href="http://yatindrarao.me/2017/07/08/how-to-add-custom-domain-and-ssl-in-heroku/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="How To Add Custom Domain And SSL in Heroku" />
      <published>2017-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-07-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://yatindrarao.me/2017/07/08/how-to-add-custom-domain-and-ssl-in-heroku</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://yatindrarao.me/2017/07/08/how-to-add-custom-domain-and-ssl-in-heroku/">&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/SqVvGx1XeUc&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although herkou provides its domain to all apps in form of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;app-name.herokuapp.com&lt;/code&gt;. We can also configure our own domain name in the app. This post is all about pointing custom domains to heroku app and also configuring SSL certificate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: For setting up SSL on Heroku you need to upgrade to paid dyno in case you are using free one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Get Domain Name&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We first need to purchase a domain name from domain providers such as Godaddy, Hostgator etc. You can also use free domains as well. For this post I am using a free domain name from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.google.co.in/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=2&amp;amp;cad=rja&amp;amp;uact=8&amp;amp;ved=0ahUKEwi4r_-t8_jUAhWIpo8KHV-wDEoQFghQMAE&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fwww.dot.tk%2F&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNGdnVqSIJXPBE3B0f-RHPo3W6fdYQ&quot;&gt;dotk&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Point Domain Name to Heroku App&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Now we will make DNS changes to point domain to our app in heroku.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From heroku &lt;strong&gt;dashboard&lt;/strong&gt; select the app which you want to configure for custom domain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Now go to Domain Name and &lt;strong&gt;Certificates section&lt;/strong&gt; in &lt;strong&gt;Settings&lt;/strong&gt;. Click on &lt;strong&gt;Add Domain&lt;/strong&gt; button and paste your domain name.&lt;br /&gt;
You can also add domain via Heroku CLI.
    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ heroku add domains:add yourdomain
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;and can also check the added domains.&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ heroku domains
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Update DNS of your domain name. Go to the DNS settings and add &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;CNAME&lt;/code&gt; record with following values&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Name&lt;/code&gt;: yourdomainname&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Value/Target&lt;/code&gt;: yourdomainname.herokudns.com&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;TTL&lt;/code&gt;: Leave it as it is&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://yatindrarao.me/assets/dns-config.png&quot; alt=&quot;DNS-Configuration&quot; /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: Replace yourdomainname with domain name you’ve purchased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visit https://yourdomainname and your app should be running on this domain now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;SSL Configuration&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can purchase a SSL certificate from many providers in the market or can also generate ** Self Signed Certificate**. Although the process of adding SSL is same in both cases.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For this post I’ve used self signed certificate by following this guide &lt;a href=&quot;https://devcenter.heroku.com/articles/ssl-certificate-self&quot;&gt;Heroku SSC Guide&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After getting the SSL certificate go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Domain Name and Certificates&lt;/code&gt; section in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Settings&lt;/code&gt; in Heroku &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Dashboard&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://yatindrarao.me/assets/ssl-config.png&quot; alt=&quot;Heroku-SSL-Config&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Go to &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Configure SSL&lt;/code&gt; -&amp;gt; &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Manually&lt;/code&gt;. Now paste certificate, key in the forms as asked and submit it. Now you’ve successfully configured the app with SSL.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Yatindra Rao</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">Although herkou provides its domain to all apps in form of app-name.herokuapp.com. We can also configure our own domain name in the app. This post is all about pointing custom domains to heroku app and also configuring SSL certificate. Note: For setting up SSL on Heroku you need to upgrade to paid dyno in case you are using free one. Get Domain Name We first need to purchase a domain name from domain providers such as Godaddy, Hostgator etc. You can also use free domains as well. For this post I am using a free domain name from dotk . Point Domain Name to Heroku App Now we will make DNS changes to point domain to our app in heroku. From heroku dashboard select the app which you want to configure for custom domain. Now go to Domain Name and Certificates section in Settings. Click on Add Domain button and paste your domain name. You can also add domain via Heroku CLI. $ heroku add domains:add yourdomain and can also check the added domains. $ heroku domains Update DNS of your domain name. Go to the DNS settings and add CNAME record with following values Name: yourdomainname Value/Target: yourdomainname.herokudns.com TTL: Leave it as it is Note: Replace yourdomainname with domain name you’ve purchased. Visit https://yourdomainname and your app should be running on this domain now. SSL Configuration You can purchase a SSL certificate from many providers in the market or can also generate ** Self Signed Certificate**. Although the process of adding SSL is same in both cases. For this post I’ve used self signed certificate by following this guide Heroku SSC Guide. After getting the SSL certificate go to Domain Name and Certificates section in Settings in Heroku Dashboard. Go to Configure SSL -&amp;gt; Manually. Now paste certificate, key in the forms as asked and submit it. Now you’ve successfully configured the app with SSL.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
  
    <entry>
      
      <title type="html">Rails Model Associations</title>
      
      <link href="http://yatindrarao.me/2017/03/23/rails-model-associations/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Rails Model Associations" />
      <published>2017-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</published>
      <updated>2017-03-23T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
      <id>http://yatindrarao.me/2017/03/23/rails-model-associations</id>
      <content type="html" xml:base="http://yatindrarao.me/2017/03/23/rails-model-associations/">&lt;p&gt;This post is about the complex assocations in Rails Active Model such as STI and Polymorphic.&lt;/p&gt;</content>

      
      
      
      
      

      
        <author>
            <name>Yatindra Rao</name>
          
          
        </author>
      

      

      

      
        <summary type="html">This post is about the complex assocations in Rails Active Model such as STI and Polymorphic.</summary>
      

      
      
    </entry>
  
  
</feed>
